Register of the Joseph Warren Stilwell papers 51001
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, 1899-1957
  - 29 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell on inspection tours of various military camps in the U.S., including Ft. Benning, Camp Croft, Ft. McClellan, Camp Fannin, and Ft. Riley, 1945 (Box-folder 86: K.1-3)
  - 11 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell on inspection tours of various military camps in the U.S., and Ft. Riley, 1945 (Box-folder 86: L.1-2)
  - 27 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell on inspection tours of various military camps in the U.S., including Ft. Benning, Camp Croft, and Ft. McClellan, 1945 (Box-folder 86: M.1-3)
  - 12 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell on inspection tours of various military camps in the U.S., including Ft. Knox and Ft. McClellan, 1945 (Box-folder 86: N.1-2)
  - 88 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell on inspection tours of various military camps in the U.S., including Ft. Benning, Camp Croft, Ft. McClellan, Camp Fannin, and Ft. Riley, 1945 (Box-folder 86: O.1-6)
  - 5 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell with General Douglas MacArthur, 1945 (Box-folder 87: P)
  - 19 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell performing official duties, 1945 (Box-folder 87: Q.1-2)
  - 2 prints depicting Chinese army activities, including the first convoy over the Stilwell Road, and celebration of V-J day in Chungking, 1945 (Box-folder 87: R)
  - 49 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and activities of the Tenth Army on Okinawa, including surrender of Japanese forces, 1945 (Box-folder 87: S.1-5)
  - 50 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and activities of the Tenth Army on Okinawa, 1945 (Box-folder 87: T.1-4)
  - 130 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and activities of the Tenth Army on Okinawa, 1945 (Box-folder 87: U.1-13)
  - 96 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and activities of the Tenth Army on Okinawa, 1945 (Box-folder 88: U.14-24)
  - 300 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and activities of the Tenth Army on Okinawa, 1945 (Box-folder 88: V.1-21)
  - 36 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell at his home in Carmel, California, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 88: W.1-4)
  - 19 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell at his home in Carmel, California, after his recall from China, 1944 (Box-folder 88: X.1-3)
  - 57 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell as Commander of the China-Burma-India Theater, 1944. Includes a postcard depicting an unidentified individual riding on a horse up to the De Anza at Calexico, California, on the Mexican border, undated (Box-folder 89: Y.1-8)
  - 6 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell as Commander of the China-Burma-India Theater, during his visit to Ft. Ord, 1943 (Box-folder 89: 7)
  - 2 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and initial contingent of officers and enlisted men sent to China-Burma-India Theater, 1942 (Box-folder 89: AA)
  - 61 prints depicting the evacuation (walk-out) of Joseph Stilwell’s command from Burma, 1942 (Box-folder 89: BB.1-5)
  - 237 prints depicting the evacuation (walk-out) of Joseph Stilwell’s command from Burma, 1942, and decorations after walk-out (Box-folder 89: CC.1-5)
  - 30 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and training activities and construction of Ft. Ord, California, while Stilwell was Commander of the 7th Division, 1941 (Box-folder 89: DD.1-5)
  - 27 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and training activities at Ft. Ord, California, while Stilwell was Commander of the 7th Division, 1941 (Box-folder 89: EE.1-5)
  - 59 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and training activities at Ft. Ord, California, while Stilwell was Commander of the 7th Division, including diagram of soldiers’ club, 1941 (Box-folder 89: FF.1-4)
  - 39 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and training activities at Ft. Ord, California, while Stilwell was Commander of the 7th Division, 1941 (Box-folder 90: GG.1-3)
  - 20 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and training activities at Ft. Ord, California, while he was Commander of the 7th Division, 1940 (Box-folder 90: HH.1-2)
  - 75 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell in 1917 with French XVII Corps and the American Expeditionary Force, France, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 90: II.1-2)
  - 4 prints depicting West Point cadets in formation at the St. Louis Exposition, 1904 (Box-folder 90: JJ)
  - 11 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell’s family, circa 1935-1946 (Box-folder 90: KK)
  - 1 print, (autographed May 24, 1945), depicting Madame Sun Yat-sen, and 1 print depicting Wei Li-huang and wife, 1944 (Box-folder 90: LL)
  - 13 prints depicting cultural and scenic sites in China, undated (Box-folder 90: MM)
  - 16 sketches depicting Joseph W. Stilwell, European architecture by E. L. Rose, and scenes from France, Germany, and Okinawa, 1917-1919; 9 cartoons depicting Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943; 16 prints, including 1 depicting Joseph W. Stilwell signing the photograph, 1941-1946; 1 print depicting Japanese surrender ceremonies on board USS Missouri autographed by Ho Ying-chin, Li Tsung-jen, C. W. Nimitz, Li-jen Sun, and Hsueh Yuen; 1 print depicting Hsueh Yuen, n.d.; 1 print depicting Li Tsung-jen, n.d.; 1 print (autographed) depicting Li-Jen sun, 1946; 1 print depicting the III Corps Color Guard, n.d.; 1 print depicting Chiang Kai-shek helping Lin Sen, n.d.; 1 print depicting Ho Ying-chin, n.d.; 1 print depicting Ambassador Nelson Johnson presenting his credentials, n.d.; 2 prints depicting castles in Germany, 1919; 1 print depicting Joseph W. Stilwell's boots and hat, n.d.; 6 prints illustrating bomb damages and intelligence operations, n.d.; and 2 prints depicting unidentified women in Okinawa (Box-folder 114: mNN)
  - 1 print depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and Claire Lee Chennault, undated (Box-folder 90: OO)
  - 34 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell as Military Attaché in China, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 90: PP.1-2)
  - 1 print depicting Joseph W. Stilwell as a West Point cadet, n.d., and 1 print depicting Winifred A. Smith (Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell), 1908 (Box-folder 90: QQ)
  - 1 album of 58 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater taken by Bernard Hoffman of Life Magazine, 1944 (Album fRR)
  - 1 album of 15 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell inspecting Ft. Benning, Georgia, 1944 December 7 (Album fSS)
  - 1 album of 8 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell inspecting Ft. Still, Oklahoma, 1945 March 16-17 (Album fTT)
  - 1 copy entitled Snapshots of China, consisting of 126 reproductions depicting scenes of China and activities of the U.S. Army in China, 15th U.S. Infantry, Tientsin, China, 1927-1928, published and compiled by The Sentinel (Album fUU)
  - 95 prints depicting Fort Benning, Georgia, including group photos of George Marshall, Joseph W. Stilwell, and others, 1929-1933 (Box-folder 90: VV.1-10)
  - 40 prints depicting maneuvers of the 2nd Division, Christine, Texas, 1940 (Box-folder 90: WW.1-3)
  - 30 prints depicting scenes of the Sino-Japanese War, including war atrocities, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 90: XX.1-3)
  - 145 prints depicting scenes of the Sino-Japanese War, including war atrocities, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 91: XX.4-10)
  - 17 prints depicting the Casablanca Conference participants, including Chiang Kai-shek, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Dwight D. Eisenhower, George C. Marshall, Madame Chiang Kai-shek, and Winston Churchill, 1943 January (Box-folder 91: YY.1-2)
  - 2 prints depicting the Dalai Lama of Tibet and the Living Buddha of Outer Mongolia, 1943 (Box-folder 91: ZZ)
  - 9 prints depicting Chiang Kai-shek and Mme Chiang Kai-shek with Joseph W. Stilwell and others, undated (Box-folder 91: AAA)
  - 174 prints depicting training of Chinese soldiers, hospitals, U.S. troops, and entertainers, China-Burma-India Theater, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 91: BBB.1-8)
  - 45 prints depicting training activities at Camp Ramgarh in India, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 91: CCC.1-7)
    Includes one print depicting the B-29 base, China Bay, Ceylon.
  - 55 prints depicting training activities of the Y-Force of the Chinese Army, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 91: DDD.1-5)
  - 68 prints depicting training activities of the Y-Force of the Chinese Army, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 92: DDD.6-11)
  - 123 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 92: EEE.1-8)
  - 71 prints depicting scenes from Kunming and Burma, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 92: FFF.1-4)
  - 117 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 92: GGG.1-9)
  - 115 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 93: HHH.1-10)
  - 98 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 93: III.1-6)
  - 118 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 93: JJJ.1-8)
  - 78 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, including Ledo Road, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 93: KKK.1-4)
  - 489 prints and 79 negatives depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 94: LLL.1-2)
  - 155 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 94: MMM.1-2)
  - 25 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, including Ledo Road, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 94: NNN.1-2)
  - 34 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 94: OOO.1-3)
    Including first convoy over Ledo Road, Mars Task Force, and Merrill's Marauder.
  - 33 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, including Mars Task Force, Myitkyina, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 94: PPP.1-3)
  - 27 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, Oran, North Africa, and Myitkyina, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 94: QQQ.1-2)
  - 25 prints depicting scenes from the China-Burma-India Theater, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 94: RRR.1-2)
    Including bridge damage in Burma, Stilwell Road, and Mars Task Force.
  - 113 prints and 114 postcards depicting daily life and cultural sites in the Philippines, Southeast Asia, and Japan, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 95: SSS.1-4)
  - 12 prints depicting the "China Room" at Harvet Barracks, Kitzingen, Germany, showing regimental colors, artifacts, and memorabilia, 1912-1938 (Box-folder 95: TTT)
  - 29 prints, unidentified or miscellaneous, circa 1914-1945 (Box-folder 95: UUU)
  - 44 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell in the China-Burma-India Theater, together with album pages containing captions to prints, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 114: mVVV)
  - 11 prints depicting aerial views of World War I battlefields, France, undated (Box-folder 114: mWWW)
  - 9 caricatures depicting military life in the American Expeditionary Forces in France during World War I, undated (Box-folder 114: mXXX)
  - 18 prints of war damage and French soldiers in France during World War I, undated (Box-folder 114: YYY)
  - 15 prints depicting unidentified German officers, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 114: ZZZ)
  - 1 aerial print depicting Toul, France; 2 German aerial prints depicting trench networks; 4 panoramic prints depicting trench networks; 20 panoramic prints depicting French locations; 1 print depicting a T-1 light tank; and 2 prints depicting the Logan Wire Cutting Machine, all from World War I period (Box-folder 114: mAAAA)
  - 1 album of 180 prints depicting people and scenes in Spain, 1914 (Album fBBBB)
  - 1 album of 302 prints depicting people and scenes in Japan and China, 1911 (Album fCCCC)
  - 1 album of 44 hand-painted prints in color depicting scenery in Japan, undated (Album fDDDD)
  - 1 album of 174 prints depicting people and scenes in Hawaii and the Philippine Islands, including American troops and ships, 1906 (Album fEEEE)
  - 1 album of 320 prints depicting people and scenes in Mexico, Philippines, and the United States, 1904-1909 (Album fFFFF)
  - 1 album of 314 prints depicting people and scenes in Mexico, 1908, Honduras, 1909, and the Philippine Islands, 1911-1912 (Album fGGGG)
  - 1 album of 171 prints, 1912; loose album sheets of 757 prints, undated; 1 envelope of 11 prints, undated; and 3 loose prints, ca. 1899, depicting Joseph W. Stilwell as a military cadet and young officer, people and scenes in the U.S. and Europe, and World War I (Album fHHHH)
  - 45 prints depicting people and scenes in Europe, including one depicting General John J. Pershing, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 95: IIII)
  - 7 prints depicting people and scenes in Honduras, circa 1908 (Box-folder 95: JJJJ)
  - 17 prints depicting boats and 3 prints depicting France, circa 1918 (Box-folder 95: KKKK)
  - 15 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell, 15th infantry, Monterey, and scenes of West Point, circa 1912 (Box-folder 95: LLLL)
  - 9 prints depicting scenes in Urga, Russia, 19 prints depicting scenes in the Far East, and 51 prints depicting unidentified scenes, circa 1918-1939 (Box-folder 95: MMMM)
  - 165 prints depicting unidentified people, primarily military personnel, circa 1918-1919 (Box-folder 95: NNNN.1-2)
  - 19 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and others, circa 1918 (Box-folder 95: OOOO)
  - 1 print depicting Joseph W. Stilwell with others, including James M. Meade and Richard B. Russell, Jr., circa 1943 (Box-folder 95: PPPP)
  - 1 album of 119 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell's visit to Ramgarh Training Center in India during World War II (Box-folder 95: fQQQQ)
  - 1 print depicting Joseph W. Stilwell's son-in-law, Ernest F. Easterbrook, in Burma with others, 1945 (Box-folder 95: RRRR)
  - 1 print depicting Ramgarh, undated; 1 print depicting the Class of 1926, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas; 2 prints depicting Chinese soldiers, 1944; 1 print depicting a plane, 1944; 1 print depicting the Military Order of the World Wars, New York Chapter, banquet and ball in observance of Army Day, New York City, April 7, 1945; 1 print depicting military attachés in China, 1930-1935; 1 print depicting foreign military attachés in Peking, including Joseph W. Stilwell, ca. 1937; 1 print depicting scenes in the Philippines, n.d.; 4 prints depicting U.S. Signal Corps activities, World War II; 1 souvenir poster-montage consisting of prints depicting members of the 12th Infantry, Philippine Islands, 1925; 1 print depicting Joseph W. Stilwell during the walk-out, 1942; and 1 unidentified print (Envelope m*SSSS)
  - 1 print depicting an aerial view of Chabua airport, India, undated; 1 print depicting Ch'ih Feng-cheng, undated; 23 prints depicting unidentified individuals carrying guns in war zone, undated; 1 print depicting Howard Smith, undated; 1 print depicting a rifle mounted on a wooden bench, Fort Ord, California, undated; 1 print depicting an unidentified individual, undated; and 26 prints depicting the plan for the "Step Child" operation (Box-folder 96: 1)
  - 1 print depicting Joseph W. Stilwell with Omar Bradley, George C. Marshall, and others, 1932-1933; 1 print depicting 3 unidentified soldiers in war zone, circa 1934-1935; 1 print depicting Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell with Mme Dan, a Manchu Princess, China, ca. 1937; 1 print depicting Bennett, Berlucci, Hiraoka, Imai, Kabutch, Kano, Overesch, Taylor, and Yamaguchi with their names written on the back by Joseph W. Stilwell, October 11, 1937; 6 prints depicting the development of ports, 1942; 12 prints depicting refugee camps, 1942; and 6 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell's plans for air cargo service over the hump, 1942 December – 1944 October (Box-folder 96: 2)
  - 1 print depicting the Nasbet (bullet proof) shock absorbing Raming plane and submarine, 1943; 22 prints depicting the Fourteenth Air Force's activities, July 1943 – October 1944; and 1 print depicting Chiang Kai-shek, Franklin D. Roosevelt, and Winston Churchill after the Cairo Conference, 1943 November (Box-folder 96: 3)
  - 4 prints depicting Assam lines of communication, 1944; 19 prints depicting traces of the Pipeline Project, 1944; 1 print depicting the Skau family, 1945; and 6 prints depicting White Sands, New Mexico, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 96: 4)
  - 1 print depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and fellow officers at Plattsburgh, 1917 (Box-folder 97: TTTT)
  - 38 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell and 2nd Division, 1940, and house at Ft. Sam, Houston, Texas (Box-folder 97: UUUU)
  - 3 prints depicting Curtis E. LeMay, Commander of the 21st Bomber Command, and others, Guam, 1945 (Box-folder 97: VVVV)
  - 9 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell, Mrs. Stilwell, and others, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 97: WWWW)
  - 10 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell, Mrs. Stilwell, and others during the Stilwells' visit to the United States to attend a conference, 1943 (Box-folder 97: XXXX)
  - 3 prints depicting Joseph W. Stilwell, H. H. Arnold, Brehon B. Somervell, and R. A. Wheeler, New Delhi, India, circa 1944 (Box-folder 97: YYYY)
  - 25 prints depicting tours of civilian manufacturing plants by the Army Ground Forces, Detroit, Michigan, 1945, including one print of military banquet and ball in commemoration of Army Day, New York, 1945 April (Box-folder 97: ZZZZ)
- Sound Recordings, 1944-1956 (Reading room workstation)
  Includes comments by Red Barber on Joseph W. Stilwell and sports; Joseph W. Stilwell speech in San Francisco; messages sent by Joseph W. Stilwell to the American people from Burma; Frank Dorn speech about Stilwell; radio dramatization about Stilwell, on three sound cassettes (CD use copies available).
  - Stilwell speech, San Francisco, circa 1946 March
    Use copy reference number: 51001_a_0000241_a01 (part)
    CD 241, tracks 1-7. Believed to be a speech at a luncheon of the Chamber of Commerce, San Francisco, 28 March 1946, based on quotes in "Gen. Stilwell Talks Back: 'Army Caste System Sounds Nasty, but Discipline Is Vital'," San Francisco Chronicle, 29 March 1946. Quoting from the article, Stilwell's talk covers "the caste system, Army brasshats, the atomic bomb, and charges of undemocratic procedures in the Army."
  - Stilwell message to the American people from Burma via the Blue Network, circa 1944
    CD 241, tracks 7-8.
  - Sports Magazine of the Air with Red Barber, presented by Columbia, circa 1946 October
    CD 241, tracks 8-9. Days after his death, Barber salutes Stilwell as soldier and athlete.
  - Stilwell message to the American people from Burma via the Blue Network, circa 1944
    Use copy reference number: 51001_a_0003278 (part)
    CD 3278, track 1.
  - Stilwell message after victory in Europe about the war in the Pacific, 1945
    CD 3278, track 2.
  - Stilwell speech, 1946
    CD 3278, track 3. Stilwell addresses criticisms of the army and urges Americans not to neglect the military.
  - Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell radio message from Carmel, California, circa 1946
    CD 3278, track 4. After her husband's death, she defends his reputation after publication of some uncomplimentary articles.
  - Stilwell message to the American people from Burma, circa 1944
    CD 3278, track 5.
  - Stilwell message after victory in Europe about the war in the Pacific, 1945
    CD 3278, track 6.
  - Stilwell speech, 1946
    CD 3278, track 7. Stilwell addresses criticisms of the army and urges Americans not to neglect the military.
  - Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell radio message from Carmel, California, circa 1946
    CD 3278, track 8. After her husband's death, she defends his reputation after publication of some uncomplimentary articles.
  - General Frank Dorn speech about Stilwell in the China-Burma-India theater during World War II, San Francisco, 1956 March 20
    Use copy reference number: 51001_a_0003277 (part)
    CD 3277, 1 of 2, track 1, introduction of Dorn; tracks 2-4, Dorn speech; tracks 4-10, questions and answers with Dorn; CD 3277, 2 of 2, tracks 1-3, questions and answers with Dorn; CD 3277, 2 of 2, track 3, Mrs. Stilwell. At the end, Mrs. Stilwell makes some remarks and brings a poem written by Stilwell, "Is Marriage a Failure?," which Dorn reads aloud. This may be a speech to the Chamber of Commerce, San Francisco.
  - Stilwell speech, San Francisco, circa 1946 March
    CD 3277, 2 of 2, tracks 4-9. Believed to be a speech at the Chamber of Commerce, San Francisco, 28 March 1946, based on quotes in "Gen. Stilwell Talks Back: 'Army Caste System Sounds Nasty, but Discipline Is Vital'," San Francisco Chronicle, 29 March 1946.
  - Stilwell message to the American people from Burma via the Blue Network, circa 1944
    CD 3277, 2 of 2, track 10.
  - "Uncle Joe," Warriors of Peace: The Story of the United States Army and 148 Years of Peacetime Service To the Nation, undated
    CD 3277, 2 of 2, tracks 11-17. Starring Walter Abel as narrator. Presented by ABC in cooperation with the U.S. Army Recruiting Service.
- Incremental Materials, 1910-2002
  Biographical information, clippings and other printed matter, circulars, correspondence, lists, maps, memoranda, notes, photographs, reports, and speeches and writings relating to Joseph W. Stilwell's life and military career, and to the issuance of a postal stamp in recognition of his service, arranged alphabetically by physical form. Includes two scrapbooks containing miscellaneous material.
  - Biographical file
    - Family travel records, 1935-1969 (Box-folder 98: 1)
    - ID card for Mrs. Joseph W. Stilwell issued in Peiping, 1938 November 29 (Box-folder 98: 2)
    - Legal record signed by Joseph W. Stilwell appointing Winifred Stilwell his "true and lawful attorney," Carmel, California, 1942 October 6 (Box-folder 86: 3)
      Includes some undated financial records.
    - Notes, 1911-1982 (Box-folder 98: 4)
      Including on Joseph W. Stilwell from the diary of Winifred Stilwell and miscellaneous notes in Chinese.
    - Poem, "Seeing Halley's Comet," by Benjamin Watson Stilwell, undated (Box-folder 98: 5)
    - Sketches, 1967 June 26 (Box-folder 98: 6)
      Includes a letter from Joseph M. O’Donnell to Barbara Tuchman.
    - Writings by others
      Relating to Joseph W. Stilwell. Includes some writings by Joseph W. Stilwell edited by others.
      - General, undated (Box-folder 98: 7)
      - "General Joseph W. Stilwell – Soldier," by John Easterbrook, undated (Box-folder 98: 8)
      - "Vinegar Joe and the Reluctant Dragon," by Samuel Lubell, Saturday Evening Post, 1945 February 24 (Box-folder 98: 9)
      - "Mourning the Death of General Stilwell," editorial comments by Ching Shih Jih Pao, Peiping, October 14, 1946, Peiping Tientsin Chinese Press Review, American Consulate, Peiping, 1946 October 15 (Box-folder 98: 10)
      - "Highlights," by Jack Bell, Miami Herald, 1947 January 12 (Box-folder 98: 11)
      - "Stilwell," poem by Ivan Becker written for Winifred Stilwell, 1948 December 4 (Box-folder 98: 12)
      - "Conversation with Barbara Tuchman," The Carmel Pine Cone, 1970 November 26 (Box-folder 86: 13)
      - "Gen. Joseph Stilwell," by Stephen Earll, Express-News Sunday Magazine, 1975 January 12 (Box-folder 98: 14)
      - Stilwell's Personal File: China-Burma-India, 1942-1944, 1976, edited by Riley Sunderland and Charles F. Romanus
        - Volumes 1-2 (Box-folder 98: 15-16)
        - Volumes 3-4 (Box-folder 99: 1-2)
        - Volume 5 (Box-folder 100: 1)
      - "George C. Marshall: The Loyal General," by Laurence S. Kuter, The Retired Officer, 1978 June (Box-folder 100: 2)
      - "WWII Pilot Is 'the Forgotten Man'," by Annabelle Armstrong, Sunday Advocate, 1983 August 21 (Box-folder 100: 3)
      - "Search for the Other Stilwell Road," by Nancy S. Easterbrook, 1988 (Box-folder 100: 4)
      - "The Best of Army Basketball," Basketball Media Guide, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 100: 5)
        Includes a copy of "Basket Ball," The Howitzer, 1904, with a listing of team members including Joseph W. Stilwell.
      - "I Am Very Proud," Nancy S. Easterbrook, China Today, 1992 February (Box-folder 100: 6)
      - "Stilwell's Role in Sino-US Relations," Chen Xiuxia, China Today, 1992 February (Box-folder 100: 7)
      - "A Test of Wills," John Grady, Army, 1994 July (Box-folder 100: 8)
      - "Our Stilwell Heritage: Writings of Ole Pappy, and Others," arranged by Deborah J. Bunce, 1999 (Box-folder 100: 9-12)
        Includes a letter to the Hoover Institution, May 18, 1999.